


















    




<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rss version="2.0"  xml:lang="en-us"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        
            <copyright>This work is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0</copyright>
        

        

        
            <language>en-us</language>
        

        
            <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 13:09:52 EST</lastBuildDate>
        

        
            <link>https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/</link>
        

        
            <atom:link href="https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/rss.xml" hreflang="en-us" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        

        
            

            <atom:link href="https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
        
            

            <atom:link href="https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/rss.xml" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        

        

        

        
            <title>Critter Corner</title>
        

        

        
            
                <item>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    

                    

                    

                    

                    

                    
                    
                    

                    

                    
                        <description><![CDATA[<h2 id=cosmology>Cosmology</h2><p>Before the beginning, there was nothing. In the very center of nothing, was everything. Everything opened its singular eye and beheld its opposite. It was a mighty creature and within itself, it contained every variation of every single possible moment, all at once. It was the mighty Worldbeast. But after eons of staring into the nothingness, its eye became bloodshot and the first crimson flower of madness began to bloom. In its fury eternity clawed at itself, finally tearing its eye asunder and fashioning the first god out of its most desperate wish, that it and every creature would one day die. The first god, the god of death took pity and struck, ending the life of the worldbeast. The nothing seeped into the gash in the corpse and ate every continuum except one. Thus it became that reality collapsed into a singular existence, moving forward an instant at a time.</p><p>Over the centuries life evolved. As souls went through countless animalistic lives, they began to become sentient, and when they were severed from their forms they would cycle anew to the next form. But this was not without consequence, for a soul cast asunder will always seek the strongest source of power, and no power in all the lands can equal that of the discarded iris of the worldbeast, known as the iris of eternity. As the souls of the many races began to flow through the iris they left groves in the shape of their greatest feelings. Their fear, their hopes, and their desires. The weight of their narratives. Thus it became so that the godhead was formed, creating a pantheon of creatures embodying the strongest passions of the living. Each one of these creatures, termed gods, devils, and fae possess the infinite power of the iris, but can only act in accordance with the stories and ideas that spawned them.</p><p>Over time these gods started to interact with mortals, changing their lives and themselves with it, and entering contracts with their worshipers, by imbedding parts of their power within the core of their souls. But opening your soul to a god is not without consequences. The more of a god is anchored to your soul, the more of their power you can wield yes, but the less of you that remains. One of the most famous paladins of light got to the point where he would do nothing in between battles but stare at the wall of the king’s throne room, unmoving and unmovable. These mortals that came to replace too much of their souls with a god&rsquo;s power came to be called &ldquo;saints&rdquo;</p><p>Seeking freedom from this bargain and the whims of the often fickle gods, the first king sought a new power that might be wielded by the kingdom of man. He found it in a small peasant child brought to his throne with a strange ailment. The child could see things that weren’t there, not an uncommon phenomenon, <em>but</em> he could also bring them here, although he couldn’t keep them here for long. After decades of studying, the kingdom had discovered the power of in-potentia. For when the worldbeast died, the alternative moments did not disappear, they simply stopped existing. Those with power in their soul could reach into the void and pull forth objects and forces from these alternate times, as long as they can figure out how these things would happen. It became known that the key to wielding in-potenia is that everything that doesn’t exist, doesn’t exist somewhere, all a mage had to do is find where.</p><p>For a time, this was good, but then the first of the mages entered the throne room and slew the first king in a fit of madness. The exposure to so much information all the time had warped his mind, allowed him to see further than his mind could handle, and he had snapped under the pressure. The first prince ordered all the mages killed, but they saw this coming and fled the kingdom.</p><p>In modern times it is understood that the practice of magic, the wielding of in-potentia is a part of the world. Mages receive training, and often call forth mundane materials for the townspeople, shaping the economy of modern societies. The mages are taught the magi’s virtues: Insight or the ability to understand the world and figure out how to pull what’s needed from in-potentia, Power or the ability to pull large objects or significant powers from the void, and fortitude or the ability to withstand the effects of magic on your mind and body.</p><p>Like in human bodies, the decaying of the worldbeast creates gasses. But unlike humans, the worldbeast’s corpse creates beautiful music. The majority of people can not hear it, however those with significant insight or power can almost make out the melody. Only those lost to madness or about to die can hear the lyrics.</p><h2 id=worldbeast-axioms>Worldbeast Axioms</h2><p>Like most settings, the worldbeast follows some general narrative rules for every story set inside it.</p><ol><li>The world is an overwhelmingly dangerous place, the more you understand about it, the more you understand how fragile and insignificant you are.</li><li>Mind control and other magical methods of mental coercion do not work. Every person in the worldbeast must make their own decisions, for better or worse.</li><li>Every character will inevitably die. Resurrection is not possible, though things like litchdom are.</li><li>Acts of in-potentia are inherently dangerous. There is no such thing as a safe spell or a sane magi.</li><li>Insight is the seeing of things that are real and true or could become so. If they are not, then it is not insight.</li><li>Gods in any form are dangerous and fickle, and the powers they offer have domain-related downsides. A fire god will offer powers that will burn the user if they are not careful for example.</li><li>Saints are self-destructive and unstable. There is no such thing as a truly useful saint.</li><li>In-potentia requires training, it can not be used on instinct, though it can be guided or directed in its raw state inside someone.</li><li>The god of death is never met and never speaks.</li><li>Eyes, music, and stories are important symbology and are never invoked lightly.</li></ol>]]></description>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:clockwork-critter.github.io,2024-04-25:/Critter-Corner/worldbeast-pages/orgin-and-rules/</guid>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/worldbeast-pages/orgin-and-rules/</link>
                    

                    
                        

                        

                        <atom:link href="https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/worldbeast-pages/orgin-and-rules/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 05:23:16 EDT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <title>Cosmology, Mythology, and Axioms</title>
                    
                </item>
            
        
            
                <item>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    

                    

                    

                    

                    

                    
                    
                    

                    

                    
                        <description><![CDATA[<h2 id=introduction>Introduction</h2><p>How many times have you had the following happen? A person joins your community and makes a post asking about how to get their WiFi working on Linux. They are new to Linux and they have an .exe file they downloaded somewhere from the internet. Or how about a person who wants to install Linux but can&rsquo;t choose a distribution and asks for the &ldquo;best one&rdquo; or better yet wanting to install &ldquo;Linux&rdquo; but not knowing what a distribution is. What explains these kinds of missteps? After all a seasoned user would easily point out the mistakes and know where to get more information. The answer lies in a phenomenon called incognizance.</p><h2 id=what-is-incognizance>What is Incognizance?</h2><p>Incognizance in information science is the state of having a particular information need but being unaware you have this need. Take for a particularly dramatic example: a patient being diagnosed with cancer. They may be so overwhelmed by the diagnosis that they don&rsquo;t have any idea what to ask their doctor. They may need to know how this will affect their day to day life or how to find emotional support but they may not know that they need these things until later. It may help to connect this concept with your life. Can you think of a time that you didn&rsquo;t know what you needed to know?</p><h2 id=why-does-it-matter>Why Does it Matter?</h2><p>If you want to make a system easier to use, you first have to understand where the problems come from before you can attempt to solve them. Going back to our previous examples, the user trying to get their wifi working doesn&rsquo;t know that they need to learn how Linux handles packages. They also need to know how to find the right driver packages. Of course the best way to solve this is to have the driver loaded by default, but this isn&rsquo;t always possible. Some distros attempt to fix this by creating a welcome tour that explains where to get your software. This prompts the user to understand that they get their software from a different place then they would on Windows, therefore reducing their incognizance.</p><p>In more generic terms: reducing incognizance means solving problems before they come up and giving people the tools to seek the information they need to solve their own problems, which means less work for everyone involved. It also helps you to have more patience with people who are new. When you understand where systems fail their users and where these problems come from it becomes easier to empathize and teach, rather than the normal Linux community refrain of RTFM or belittling them. And that is a goal well worth considering.</p>]]></description>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:clockwork-critter.github.io,2025-02-17:/Critter-Corner/blog/incognizance-and-linux/</guid>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/blog/incognizance-and-linux/</link>
                    

                    
                        

                        

                        <atom:link href="https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/blog/incognizance-and-linux/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 13:09:52 EST</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <title>Incognizance and Linux</title>
                    
                </item>
            
        
            
                <item>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    

                    

                    

                    

                    

                    
                    
                    

                    

                    
                        <description><![CDATA[<h3 id=windows-pros>Windows Pros</h3><ol><li><p>Compatible with most software including games.</p><ul><li>If it runs it probably runs on Windows. This incudes really old programs and obscure games.</li></ul></li><li><p>Difficult to break, easy to maintain</p><ul><li>Windows can be broken but it does require doing something stupid and it can be much easier to recover than Linux depending on how you messed up. A broken update can easily be undone sometimes even automatically for example, though newer Linux systems like Fedora Silverblue and NixOS do surpass or rival it in this regard.</li></ul></li></ol><h3 id=windows-cons>Windows Cons</h3><ol><li>Difficult installations<ul><li>On Windows it&rsquo;s not uncommon to have to chew through a few installers to set up the software you need.</li></ul></li><li>Inflexible UX<ul><li>On Windows you can&rsquo;t move your taskbar to the side and you have very limited options for customization.</li></ul></li><li>The Spectre of AI integration<ul><li>This won&rsquo;t be a problem for everyone but the integrity of my information is very important to me. The encroachment of AI and LLMs into windows means I have to be careful when an LLM might be injecting information or digesting my writing for analysis and training</li></ul></li></ol><h3 id=linux-pros>Linux Pros</h3><ol><li>Software Availability<ul><li>On linux if software is available you grab it from the software store or maybe the package manager and get going.</li></ul></li><li>UX flexibility<ul><li>On linux you can have the UX work however you&rsquo;d like thanks to GNOME extensions or KDE plasma or the massive collection of Window Managers out there. If you can dream it, there&rsquo;s a way to do it on linux.</li></ul></li><li>The command line<ul><li>Linux allows a lot of flexibility through it&rsquo;s command line. While windows has this as well, Linux allows you to change or do just about anything through the terminal</li></ul></li></ol><h3 id=linux-cons>Linux Cons</h3><ol><li>Installing software not available through the store or your OS&rsquo;s repos can be a real pain<ul><li>Weird extra package managers, manual compilation, random appimage files and more, things not packaged for your OS can be a real pain to get working. The upside to this is that you can install even the weird stuff and with a little elbow grease you might even get to package it yourself to spare others the pain you went through</li></ul></li><li>The 99% rule<ul><li>99% of your desktop will work really well! However there will always be a few annoying bugs you can&rsquo;t fix with your hardware or a few features that don&rsquo;t quite work. It&rsquo;s annoying and it&rsquo;s up to every person if it&rsquo;s worth it compared to Linux&rsquo;s competitors.</li></ul></li><li>Unlimited Footgun Ammunition<ul><li>If you want to do something stupid linux won&rsquo;t stop you! Especially through the terminal. This can make the learning process quite frustrating.</li></ul></li></ol>]]></description>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:clockwork-critter.github.io,2024-05-27:/Critter-Corner/blog/windows-vs-linux/</guid>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/blog/windows-vs-linux/</link>
                    

                    
                        

                        

                        <atom:link href="https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/blog/windows-vs-linux/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 09:25:41 EDT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <title>Windows vs Linux</title>
                    
                </item>
            
        
            
                <item>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    

                    

                    

                    

                    

                    
                    
                    

                    

                    
                        <description><![CDATA[<h2 id=on-names>On Names</h2><p>I have always been a believer in the importance of a name. What we call things reflects how we interact with them. I used this principle when choosing my chosen name, picking something I believed fit my personality and my values. A username however is different. A username is not just a reflection of who you are, but a key part of shaping the way people respond to you online. A username can shape the gender people assign to you, but it can also impart a lot of personality that a first name can not. This is because a username is expected to be creative, whereas a name is meant to simply represent a person. This isn&rsquo;t to say a username is more important but to say that it has different affordances than a real name.</p><h2 id=the-clockwork>The Clockwork</h2><p>I have always been fascinated by complex systems. The computer, the cell, human bodies, the list goes on. There is something endlessly fascinating about a bunch of lesser parts working together in order. And nothing summarizes this feeling for me more than clockwork. I love listening to the gears tick and watching them move on the pocketwatch my brother bought for me is so relaxing. It calls to mind a regimented, meticulous person(despite the number of spelling and grammatical errors this blog will no doubt contain), who enjoys fine details which is how I like people to think of me. Therefore, the Clockwork part of the name felt perfectly natural. In addition, while I often struggle to identify body sensations like muscle pain or hunger, visualizing myself as made of gears makes them easier to identify, which makes my affinity for the term even stronger.</p><h2 id=the-critter>The Critter</h2><p>When we think of a human a lot of things come to mind. Jobs, school, marriage, and a plethora of other assorted societal expectations for what one is supposed to do. So while I am physically a human, I like to use the word critter to detach myself from them when making decisions about what I should do. That way even when I make these decisions it is more likely that I am doing what I think is best rather than following precedent. In addition, critter is an endearing and friendly sounding word which is the energy I try to bring into my interactions with people whose company I enjoy.</p>]]></description>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:clockwork-critter.github.io,2024-04-22:/Critter-Corner/blog/choosing-a-username/</guid>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/blog/choosing-a-username/</link>
                    

                    
                        

                        

                        <atom:link href="https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/blog/choosing-a-username/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:59:46 EDT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <title>Choosing a Username</title>
                    
                </item>
            
        
            
                <item>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    

                    

                    

                    

                    

                    
                    
                    

                    

                    
                        <description><![CDATA[<h3 id=websites-and-social-media>Websites and Social Media</h3><p>In the early days of the internet, years before I would use it at all, it was commonplace to have personal websites. Then I am told came social media sites. They provided an easier way to get your thoughts out into the world. No code, markup, or page design is needed; just write and get directly to sharing. This came with a big boom in popularity for the internet in general as well as these sites in particular; to not use them was to become irrelevant, at least in the eyes of the net. The biggest social media platforms have user counts in the tens and sometimes even hundreds of millions, using their platforms to broadcast their ideas every day. That&rsquo;s a lot of posts. In fact, according to <a href=https://www.internetlivestats.com/one-second/#tweets-band rel=external>InternetLiveStats</a>
Twitter sees 6,000 tweets a second. There, of course, comes a new problem. I&rsquo;d call this the modern problem. There is so much of everyone&rsquo;s thoughts that everything becomes ephemeral; even when posts stay up for long periods, they are functionally &ldquo;gone,&rdquo; or better to say irrelevant, within a day. This is unless you have either a large amount of money or insight into a sizeable chunk of the user base. Given that we are presumably possessed by neither our options for cataloging our thoughts despite the best efforts of many are to be irrelevant to the affordances of either social media or those of a website.</p><h3 id=the-affordances-of-social-media>The Affordances of Social Media</h3><p>It is reasonable to assume that because this is written on a website I am against social media but this is not so. In fact, on my main page, I have several social media pages. Social media has the advantage of allowing people to share content with friends and share a uniform experience with other users. Social media is at its best when it allows people to share small portions of their work, short thoughts or experiences with other people, especially fast-moving things like status updates or project announcements. I use social media to get updates from artists, tech projects, and personal friends. I also use it to discuss my interests with other like-minded individuals. Social media is at its best when it is used as a connective medium, it isn’t for creating a repository of thoughts as much as it is to connect people.</p><h3 id=the-affordances-of-a-website>The Affordances of a Website</h3><p>So, when does one want to make a website? Well, a personal website is static. As long as it is maintained it provides the same content to each visitor. This means that is a better storage medium for thoughts and opinions, especially longer-form ones. This was one of the major objectives for making this website. As I progress to my professional life, and work through my academic life, I find myself with more thoughts in need of an outlet. The static nature of a website of this nature is ideal for this because it allows me to look and refer back to these thoughts as needed. In contrast, things like reach and allowing others to comment on the site are less important and thus social media is less appropriate.</p><h3 id=how-the-site-was-made-and-why>How the Site was Made and Why</h3><p>This website is hosted on <a href=https://neocities.org/ rel=external>Neocities</a>
and created directly in HTML and CSS. To make new pages and test layout changes I use <a href=https://vscodium.com/ rel=external>Visual Studio Codium</a>
, a free software build of VSCode with the telemetry removed with the extension <a href=https://github.com/yandeu/five-server rel=external>Five Server</a>
to let me make live changes and see the results instantly. With plenty of simpler options, like WordPress, why make a website this way? Well, it&rsquo;s because as an information sciences student having a variety of skills is useful. This site serves as an excuse to learn HTML and CSS, and it allows me to practice self-teaching complex technical skills, a meta-skill that is very important for a fast-paced environment like the tech industry.</p><h3 id=how-the-site-was-made-and-why-redux>How the Site was Made and Why (Redux)</h3><p>Recently I decided to change the site-building process from my own HTML and CSS to Hugo, a static site generator. This enables much faster website creation and makes it easier for me to correctly group content. This new version of the site will be hosted on a static web host, GitHub Pages, and given a custom domain (which, unlike neocities, GitHub offers the use of custom domains for free!)</p>]]></description>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:clockwork-critter.github.io,2024-04-11:/Critter-Corner/blog/the-making-of-a-website/</guid>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/blog/the-making-of-a-website/</link>
                    

                    
                        

                        

                        <atom:link href="https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/blog/the-making-of-a-website/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 08:54:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <title>The Making of a Website</title>
                    
                </item>
            
        
            
                <item>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    

                    

                    

                    

                    

                    
                    
                    

                    

                    
                        <description><![CDATA[<h2 id=general-resources>General Resources</h2><hr><p>These resources cover a lot of ground. They don&rsquo;t focus on one thing, or they deal with more general concerns.</p><ul><li><p><a href=https://www.lgbtnearme.org/ rel=external>LGBT Near Me</a></p><ul><li>This site helps you locate Trans and other Queer resources in your area.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://transequality.org rel=external>The National Center for Transgender Equality</a></p><ul><li>This site contains information on name and gender changes by state as well as other important information about rights and the navigation of various structures, such as insurance.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://genderdysphoria.fyi/ rel=external>That&rsquo;s Gender Dysphoria FYI</a></p><ul><li>This resource is aimed at questioning trans folks. Does a good job of providing an inside look at the trans experience.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://transfemscience.org/ rel=external>Transfem Science</a></p><ul><li>Provides good summaries of the scientific literature concerning MTF transitions.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.silversprocket.net/2021/09/13/a-self-defense-study-guide-for-trans-women-and-gender-non-conforming-nonbinary-amab-folks/ rel=external>A Self Defense Study Guide for Trans Women and Gender Non-Conforming/Nonbinary AMAB Folks</a></p><ul><li>A guide for self-defense based on common scenarios faced by trans and nonbinary people.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.queeringthemap.com/ rel=external>Queering the Map</a></p><ul><li>A map with a compilation of queer experiences submitted anonymously on a map. Wherever you are, find people with experiences like yours.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.translifeline.org/ rel=external>Trans Lifeline</a></p><ul><li>Emotional support hotline and microgrants organization by and for trans people.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://search.worldcat.org/title/Safe-and-sound-:-a-renter-friendly-guide-to-home-repair/oclc/1393439855/ rel=external>Safe and sound: a renter-friendly guide to home repair</a></p><ul><li>A book that walks through getting an apartment, working with management, and fixing issues that come up, written by a trans woman with an emphasis on challenges faced by minorities.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://employeejustice.com/lgbtq-discrimination-in-the-workplace/ rel=external>LGBTQ Discrimination in the Workplace</a></p><ul><li>A good primer on LGBTQ+ Workplace Discrimination and what can be done about it. Not an endorsement of the services they offer.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.rainbowrailroad.org rel=external>Rainbow Railroad</a></p><ul><li>An Organization that helps LGBTQ+ people in hostile countries get to safety.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://transrescue.org rel=external>Trans Rescue</a></p><ul><li>An Organization that helps LGBTQ+ people in hostile countries get to safety.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 id=medical-resources>Medical Resources</h2><hr><p>These resources help connect trans people with the health care they need.</p><ul><li><p><a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/viewer?mid=1DxyOTw8dI8n96BHFF2JVUMK7bXsRKtzA&amp;usp=sharing" rel=external>Erin&rsquo;s Informed Consent HRT map of the US</a></p><ul><li>A map of Informed Consent Trans Healthcare providers in the United States.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://thegalap.org/ rel=external>Gender Affirmative Letter Access Project</a></p><ul><li>A project to help connect trans people with letters for Gender Affirming Care. Often useful for navigating insurance as well as legal name changes.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://getplume.co/ rel=external>Plume</a></p><ul><li>A telehealth service for accessing HRT. Accepts some insurance plans or requires direct payment in the form of a subscription for their services.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://queermed.com/ rel=external>QueerMed</a></p><ul><li>A telehealth service for accessing HRT. Accepts some insurance plans.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.allegromedical.com/ rel=external>Allegro Medical</a></p><ul><li>A medical supply store that allows for the purchase of syringes without a prescription, as well as other medical goods.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.rainbowalphabetcollective.org/ rel=external>Rainbow Alphabet Collective</a></p><ul><li>A website that contains a list of WPATH-compliant healthcare and mental care providers.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://costplusdrugs.com/ rel=external>Cost Plus Drug Company</a></p><ul><li>A low-cost store to get prescription medications without insurance.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.goodrx.com/ rel=external>Good RX</a></p><ul><li>A website that allows comparative shopping for medications.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://transharmreduction.org rel=external>Trans Harm Reduction</a></p><ul><li>A website that tests DIY medication sources and provides instructions for injection and getting clean injection supplies.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 id=surgical-resources>Surgical Resources</h2><hr><p>Provides resources for transgender people connecting to surgical healthcare. Inclusion is not an endorsement of surgical performance.</p><ul><li><p><a href=https://www.transhealthcare.org/ rel=external>TransHealthcare.org</a></p><ul><li>A website for finding Surgeons to perform a variety of surgeries for trans people.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.phallo.net/ rel=external>Phallo.net</a></p><ul><li>Informational site on Phalloplasty. Overviews of different surgery techniques and technologies.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.mtfsurgery.net/ rel=external>MTFsurgery.net</a></p><ul><li>Informational site on MTF Surgeries. Overviews of different surgery techniques and technologies.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.ftmsurgery.net rel=external>FTMsurgery.net</a></p><ul><li>Informational site on FTM Surgeries. Overviews of different surgery techniques and technologies.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.metoidioplasty.net/ rel=external>Metoidioplasty.net</a></p><ul><li>Informational site on Metoidioplasty. Overviews of different surgery techniques and technologies.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://mexicotransgendercenter.us/service/orchiectomy-nullification/ rel=external>Mexico Transgender Center Gender Nullification</a></p><ul><li>Provides the most detailed overview of Gender Nullification Surgery. Contains some graphic medical photos.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://beesbuzz.biz/articles/5195-nullification-surgery rel=external>AMAB-to-neutrois GRS</a></p><ul><li>Provides a first-person account of Gender Nullification Surgery.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href="https://youtu.be/3u0Icd2BW7o?si=xqcxKvgKfwxLy3Ev" rel=external>How To Treat Top Surgery Scars (According To Science!) | FTMFAQ</a></p><ul><li>Provides a detailed look at scar care information for trans masculine people.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.rainbowalphabetcollective.org/post/caring-for-someone-after-a-double-mastectomy-top-surgery rel=external>Caring For Someone After a Double Mastectomy (Top Surgery)</a></p><ul><li>Provides instructions for care of trans masculine people after top surgery.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.lelaburris.com/prep-house-surgery/ rel=external>How To Prep Your House Before Having Surgery</a></p><ul><li>Provides instructions for care of people after a surgery of any kind.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.transbucket.com rel=external>TransBucket</a></p><ul><li>Provides a platform for sharing trans surgery pictures and reviews. Requires an account to view.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 id=funding-resources>Funding Resources</h2><hr><p>Transition can be expensive. To help those who can&rsquo;t afford it, these organizations help people access gender-affirming care.</p><ul><li><p><a href=https://transhealthproject.org/ rel=external>TransHealthProject.org</a></p><ul><li>A resource for navigating insurance barriers to gender-affirming care.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://getplume.co/hrt-access-fund/ rel=external>Plume HRT Access Fund</a></p><ul><li>Plume&rsquo;s Grant Fund for accessing HRT.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://jimcollinsfoundation.org/ rel=external>Jim Collins Foundation</a></p><ul><li>Helps Trans people to fund gender-affirming surgeries that they otherwise could not afford.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.pointofpride.org/hrt-access-fund rel=external>Point Of Pride HRT Access Fund</a></p><ul><li>Fund to help trans people with financial need to access telehealth HRT.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://rizitimane.com/trans-surgery-scholarship-application/ rel=external>Dr Rizi&rsquo;s Trans Surgery Grant</a></p><ul><li>Fund to help trans people access gender-affirming surgeries that they otherwise could not afford.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.pointofpride.org/annual-transgender-surgery-fund rel=external>Point Of Pride Trans Surgery Fund</a></p><ul><li>Fund to help trans people access gender-affirming surgeries that they otherwise could not afford.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.genderbands.org/grants rel=external>Genderbands Transition Grants</a></p><ul><li>Fund to help trans people access gender-affirming care and legal resources of various types that they otherwise could not afford.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.out2enroll.org rel=external>Out2Enroll</a></p><ul><li>Provides advice for purchasing health insurance for gender affirming care.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 id=voice-training-resources>Voice Training Resources</h2><hr><p>Find your authentic voice with these resources for vocal training.</p><ul><li><p><a href=https://www.youtube.com/@TransVoiceLessons rel=external>Trans Voice Lessons</a></p><ul><li>YouTube channel that teaches trans people to direct their vocal training.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.buymeacoffee.com/alyssavt rel=external>Alyssavt</a></p><ul><li>Provides text and audio instructions for trans people to direct their vocal training. Also provides a community through Discord for people undergoing voice training to help each other as well as private lessons.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://transvocaltraining.com/book-online/ rel=external>Trans Vocal Training</a></p><ul><li>Provides Group and one-on-one vocal training, as well as a self-study course.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.yourlessonsnow.com/ rel=external>Your Lessons Now</a></p><ul><li>Provides Group and one-on-one vocal training.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://devextras.com/voicetools// rel=external>Voice Tools</a></p><ul><li>Helps track pitch and intonation and guides in moving them into a feminine or masculine range. Does not provide guidance on resonance which is required for effective voice training.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://wiki.sumianvoice.com/ rel=external>Voice Resource Repository</a></p><ul><li>A collaborative wiki for explaining voice training concepts.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://transvoice.party rel=external>Trans Voice Party</a></p><ul><li>A small repository for hosting trans voice training resources</li></ul></li></ul><h2 id=style-and-hair-removal-resources>Style and Hair Removal Resources</h2><hr><p>Making adjustments to your style can be overwhelming. Here are some resources to help!</p><ul><li><p><a href=https://strandsfortrans.org/ rel=external>Strands For Trans</a></p><ul><li>A website for finding trans-friendly hair stylists.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://enfemmestyle.com/ rel=external>Enfemme Style</a></p><ul><li>A clothing brand for trans women and feminine people.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.realsimple.com/beauty-fashion/clothing/shopping-guide/how-to-measure-bra-size rel=external>Bra Size Measurement</a></p><ul><li>For people who have been on HRT for a while, going bra shopping can be a lot. This is a quick guide for anyone to get their size at home.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.aad.org/public/everyday-care/skin-care-basics/hair/how-to-shave rel=external>How to Shave</a></p><ul><li>A quick guide on how to shave. This should be generally applicable to every part of the body, but there are more specific guides out there for particular parts of the body.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.shaverater.com/learn/types-of-razors/ rel=external>Types of Razors</a></p><ul><li>A rundown of the different types of razors. One note, I don&rsquo;t ever recommend using a straight razor as it is very easy to injure yourself with little benefit.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://leafshave.com/ rel=external>Leaf Shave</a></p><ul><li>A hybrid between a cartridge razor and a safety razor. Interesting additional option for those looking to combine the advantages of both types.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.healthline.com/health/epilator#how-to-use rel=external>How to Epilate</a></p><ul><li>A guide on how to epilate. If you have the pain tolerance for it, it&rsquo;s a fantastic option for longer-lasting hair removal compared to shaving.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.youtube.com/@RobertWelsh rel=external>Robert Welsh</a></p><ul><li>A guide on how to do makeup from a professional artist covers picking products and fundamental techniques.</li></ul></li><li><p>[Hair Has No Gender]</p><ul><li><pre><code>* A website for finding trans-friendly hair stylists.
</code></pre></li></ul></li></ul><h2 id=trans-sex-education-resources>Trans Sex Education Resources</h2><hr><p>A cause close to my heart. Taking ownership of your sexuality is a daunting task, especially for transgender people. These resources can help you navigate your own unique sexuality. Some content may be 18+, please follow site policy and local laws.</p><ul><li><p><a href=https://luciefielding.com/book rel=external>Trans Sex by Lucie Fielding</a></p><ul><li>One of my favorite books. Written for clinicians, but provides enough guidance and clear language for everyday people to understand and explore themselves. This book guides readers to understand their unique relationship with their body.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://transreads.org/fucking-trans-women/ rel=external>Fucking Trans Women by Mira Bellwether</a></p><ul><li>This Zine guides trans women through alternative ways to explore their bodies, as well as guiding them on how to communicate with partners. Also provides guidance on genital anatomy.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://transsexzine.com/ rel=external>Trans Sex Zine</a></p><ul><li>A Zine exploring several perspectives on trans sexuality. Useful for inspiration in combination with other resources.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.rainbowhealthontario.ca/resource-library/primed-the-back-pocket-guide-for-trans-men-and-the-men-who-dig-them/ rel=external>The Back Pocket Guide for Trans Men and the Men Who Dig Them</a></p><ul><li>A sexual health guide for trans men and gay men who want to enter a relationship with them.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RK8fv7i6v5A" rel=external>Sexplanations with Dr. Lindsey Doe: Trans Sex</a></p><ul><li>The episode of Sexplanations on Transgender Sexuality. Contains useful ideas for partners. This channel in general is a great resource for eclectic topics in sex education.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://www.bedsider.org/ rel=external>Bedsider</a></p><ul><li>An informational resource on birth control and STI protection methods and their advantages and drawbacks. Note that gender-affirming hormone therapy is <strong>not</strong> birth control.</li></ul></li><li><p><a href=https://callen-lorde.org/graphics/2021/02/PUMP-TMSM-Health-Guide_Final_V3.2.pdf rel=external>PUMP: Sexual Pleasure & Health Resource Guide for Transmen who have Sex with Men</a></p><ul><li>An informational resource for trans men who want to have sex with other men.</li></ul></li></ul>]]></description>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:clockwork-critter.github.io,0001-01-01:/Critter-Corner/resources/trans-resources/</guid>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/resources/trans-resources/</link>
                    

                    
                        

                        

                        <atom:link href="https://clockwork-critter.github.io/Critter-Corner/resources/trans-resources/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <title>Trans Resources</title>
                    
                </item>
            
        
    </channel>
</rss>
